tips-and-tricks.co 2019-11-29

# Privacy Policy -

We understand that privacy is very important to every internet user these days. That is why we’d like to inform you on this matter. What data we collect; how we collect it; what we do with this information and how we treat it: you will read all about it on this page. WeBlog Media B.V., the company behind Tips-and-tricks.co, places a lot of value on the privacy of every visitor to our website. That’s why we make sure that the data you leave with us is kept completely confidential. WeBlog Media B.V. acts in accordance with the Personal Data Protection Act and, since May 25 2018, the General Data Protection Regulation, as far as this is applicable to us.

At the present time our website does not offer the possibility to create user profiles, comment on articles, or buy products. We also don’t provide the option to register for a newsletter with your personal information. Only by filling in our contact form will we receive your personalized data, but this is limited to the information you fill in yourself. We do use (depersonalized) data to make sure our website runs properly/better. We collect this information through functional and analytical cookies. We also place marketing cookies, but only with your consent. You can read more about this in our Cookie Statement.

It is obligatory for all of WeBlog Media B.V.’s employees to respect the confidentiality of your data.

  1. **Who are we?**

WeBlog Media B.V. is a private company, established and with office in Groningen, the Netherlands, and registered with the Commercial Register of the Dutch Chamber of Commerce under number 66136636.

  2. **What type of personal data do we collect and process?**

__Our services using personal data  
__ As stated before, Tips and Tricks does not provide the possibility to create a user profile. It’s also impossible to comment on articles, buy products via our website or register for a newsletter. This already precludes a very common reason for collecting your personal data from applying to us.

__Collecting and processing contact information  
__ We do offer the possibility to fill in a contact form in order to contact our editorial team with a question or remark. This contact form requires you to fill in your email address, so our team can process the question/remark and provide you with an answer. Without this information, we can’t approach you. Before you send your contact form, you are asked to give permission for us to save your filled in information. This data is consequently saved to the secure servers of Dutch company [Transip B.V.](https://www.transip.nl/)

__Collecting and processing automatically generated statistical data  
__ To make sure the website runs optimally and to keep improving, information about your use of our website is automatically processed. Optimizing our website mostly has to do with technical adjustments that, for example, make sure our pages are shown properly and that they are secure and protected. The information that is processed consists of, for example, the type of device you use (desktop, mobile, tablet), your IP address (your device’s internet address that is often linked to your general location), which browser you use, the operating system you use, the pages you visit on our website and where you came from before landing on our website. This is depersonalized data and it’s impossible to trace it back to you. This information is gathered through placing analytical cookies. You can read more about this in our Cookie Statement.

__Processing data for marketing purposes  
__ Of course, we hope that you visit our website because you’re interested in our content. To be able to finance new content appearing on our website on a frequent basis, we have to get our revenue from advertisements. Our goal is to make the advertisements we show you as relevant to you as possible. To be able to do this we turn to third parties for help, but only with your explicit permission. These third parties collect data about websites you’ve visited previously, products you’ve viewed, your clicking behavior or your online interests to consequently show you an advertisement you will find interesting. This data is processed, with your consent, by placing an advertisement. You can read more about this in our Cookie Statement and if you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies please [click here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). WeBlog Media B.V. does not have access to this information and does not save it anywhere.

__Processing data for social media purposes  
__ On our website, we provide the option to share articles, videos and images via social media. For this purpose we’ve placed social media share buttons for Facebook, Instagram and Pinterest. To make sure these buttons function properly social media cookies are placed, after you’ve given your consent. The minute you click one of the share buttons, Facebook, Instagram or Pinterest know who you are and you don’t have to log in to your social media account again. WeBlog Media B.V. does not save or have access to the data used by these parties. You can read more about this in our Cookie Statement.

  3. **What do we use the collected data for and what legal bases do we rely on?**

__Purposes  
__ We’ve already described this above, but collecting and processing the necessary contact information and processing depersonalized statistical data is necessary to:

  * Enable you using the website;
  * Be able to respond to questions and remarks you send us via the contact form;
  * Draw up anonymous statistical data;
  * Protect, adjust and improve the website.

_Collecting and processing contact information and processing statistical data is necessary for safeguarding the legitimate interests of WeBlog Media B.V., and can therefore not be refused _.__

If you are okay with WeBlog Media B.V. providing information about you to third parties for marketing or social media purposes, you will need to give your explicit consent on our website. You can read more about this in our Cookie Statement. With your permission, depersonalized data will be processed to be able to:

  * Show relevant and interesting advertisements
  * Share our articles
  * Make sure the same advertisement isn’t shown again and again
  * Track what other websites you visit

_Processing depersonalized data intended for marketing and social media purposes is not obligatory and it up to you as a user of our website to give your permission or not. WeBlog Media B.V. is legally obligated to obtain your permission before processing this data._

__Usage of your data by third parties  
__ The data we collect and process does not get shared with third parties, unless you have explicitly given us permission to do so. Personal information filled out by you in the contact form will _never_ be sent to third parties, _unless_ you have given your explicit permission to us. You can withdraw your permission at any time. You can do this by contacting us.

In our Cookie Statement you will find a list of the partners with whom we share the depersonalized analytical and functional cookies and, only with your permission, the data used for marketing and social media purposes.

WeBlog Media B.V. will make sure appropriate measures will be taken if we have provided your personal information to third parties. For example, WeBlog Media B.V. will, if need be, conclude a processing agreement with a third party. This agreement will include limits regarding the usage of your personal information as well as obligations regarding the protection of your personal information.

Finally, WeBlog Media B.V. can provide your personal information to third parties when we are obligated to do so based on laws and regulations, or if we are forced to do so due to a lawsuit and/or in case we deem it necessary for the protection of our own rights.

__Hyperlinks by third parties  
__ Our website can contain hyperlinks. If you click this hyperlink you will leave our website and go to another company’s website. At that point, WeBlog Media B.V. does not have any influence on the services offered by the website in question or on the website’s methods. These websites have their own privacy policy that is completely separate from our privacy policy. Our privacy policy only refers to data processed by WeBlog Media B.V. Therefore, WeBlog Media B.V. does not accept any responsibility or liability for services and/or websites by third parties or their methods and/or contents.

  4. **How long do we keep your personal information for?**

The data that is collected automatically (so, the statistical, marketing and social media data) isn’t saved by us, but merely forwarded directly by us. You can check with the receiving party how long this data is saved for. Read more about this in our Cookie Statement.

We will only store your personal data submitted via the contact form for as long as necessary for the purposes they were collected and processed in the first place. Your personal information can often be deleted as soon as we’ve dealt with your question or remark. Only when we are legally obliged to do so or when we need it to defend our interests (for example, in case of a dispute between you and us) will we store your personal data for a longer period of time.

  5. **Where do we store your personal data?**

For the hosting of our websites as well as the storage of any personal data, WeBlog Media B.V. makes use of the servers of Dutch company [Transip B.V.](https://www.transip.nl/) The servers are based in the Netherlands.

  6. **How is your personal information protected?**

WeBlog Media B.V. does everything in its power to make sure the collected data is stored safely. That is why we have a couple of very handy technical staff members who are always busy to take technical and organizational measures to enable this. We do this to protect your data from being lost or being processed unlawfully in any way. Do you want to know more about how we do this? Contact us via the contact form.

  7. **Cookies**

As stated before, we use cookies, pixels (or similar techniques) and social media plugins on ours website. Some of these cookies are necessary to make sure the websites functions properly and others help us to improve our website and to enable us to show you the right advertisements and articles. We provide you with an elaborate explanation in our Cookie Statement.

  8. **Access, improvement and transferability of your data**

If you want to know which of your personal data we have stored, you can submit a request via our contact form. This is only possible for the personal data we gather. The data we merely process cannot be called upon retroactively. This means that the only data you can have access to is the information you have submitted to us by means of the contact form. If you want to apply any changes to the information you have requested, you can let our member of staff who has helped you with the request know about it. You can request from them that WeBlog Media B.V. changes, improves, complements, deletes or screens off your data in another way.

You also have the right to be supplied with the personal data you submitted in a common, structured and readable form and to consequently transfer this data yourself. The same procedure applies here: you can send your request to us via the contact form. WeBlog Media B.V. will respond to your request within one month. In exceptional cases, WeBlog Media B.V. has the legal right to respond to your request within a three month period, for example when the request is very complex. If this is the case, WeBlog Media B.V. will let you know within one month.

If WeBlog Media B.V. refuses your request, we will notify you in writing.

  9. **Can I refuse my personal data being used?**

We need the personal data you provide us with when you contact us to be able to respond to your question or remark. We cannot respond to anonymous submissions. The usage of depersonalized data we process for functional and analytical purposes cannot be refused, except by completely blocking the use of cookies in your web browser. Read more about this in our Cookie Statement. The usage of depersonalized data for marketing and social media purposes can be refused by not consenting to it when you are asked permission while visiting our website.

  10. **Can this Privacy Policy be changed?**

This privacy policy can be changed. This statement can be altered without our visitors actively being informed. That’s why we recommend you to regularly visit this page to find out if anything has changed since your last visit.

  11. **Where can you leave a complaint?**

Do you have a complaint about the usage of your personal data and is it impossible to work it out with WeBlog Media B.V.? Then you can submit your complaint at the [Dutch DPA](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/nl/zelf-doen/privacyrechten/klacht-over-gebruik-persoonsgegevens).

  12. **Questions and feedback**

WeBlog Media B.V. regularly check whether this privacy policy is in compliance with laws and regulations. If you have any questions about our privacy policy you can submit it via the contact form or send us a letter at the following address:

WeBlog Media B.V.  
Viaductstraat 3-19  
9725 BG  
Groningen

We will be happy to answer your questions!
